Using the presentation that I created
in session one, I now need to add some
further information into the slideshow.
So I have the four slides and all they
contain at the moment is some text.
Now on slide two, I'm going to add
a chart, but I'm also going to show
how this could be added as a table.
So you do have options.
There's various things that you
can insert, but I'm going to add
a chart to this, but I will also
demonstrate how you can show that
information in the table if you prefer.
So the first thing I need to do is,
looking at the layout of the slide, it
isn't really suitable for adding a chart
or a table unless I place it underneath.
But the first thing I need to do,
and the easiest way to add a chart
or a table alongside text is to
change the layout of the slide.
So if I go to the Slides icon
and then select the layout, this
will tell me that currently this
is a title and content slide.
Now I want to change that
to a title and two content.
So if I do that, it automatically
changes it on the slide and PowerPoint
kindly pops up some design ideas.
I don't wish to use them.
So I'll just click off that.
So quite simply, I am now able to insert
a range of objects into the slide.
And if you click on each of the icons,
it will tell you what each one is.
Now the first instance, I'm just going
to insert a table just to demonstrate
so I can select insert table.
And it asks me for the
number of columns and rows.
Now I have the information
on a spreadsheet.
here, so I know it needs
two columns and seven rows.
So if I just select two
columns, seven rows, select OK.
Now that has created the table.
So I still need to populate a table.
So what I would need to do is I need to
go to my spreadsheet, use Control C to
select the data, select the presentation,
click in the first box and then Control
and V which would then paste information
in, and then I could make adjustments,
as you can see, the text is quite small
at the moment so I can go to home.
I change that to whichever text I wish,
I'll go for Arial, make it size 60, and
then I can also resize the table to suit.
If I just click on the table, I can
then change the table style and add
various other formatting options.
So that is how you would insert
a table into the presentation.
I'm just going to undo that because
what I want to add is actually a chart.
So what I'm going to do is, again,
there are two ways you can do that.
If you click on the insert chart and then
select the type of chart that you wish.
I'm going to insert a line chart and click
on line and it will give me a default
chart and I can see which one I like
and I'll just go for stack line, line.
So there's various charts
that you can select.
I'm just going to go for a line chart.
Select OK.
Now, again, it has inserted the chart
but I still have to add the information.
So I would need to take the
information that is here and
place it into this one here.
Or alternatively, I can just undo what
I did on there so I'll click the undo.
And all I would need to do then is
I have a chart that I've actually
created in Excel using that data.
So I'll just select that and
copy that, go to the PowerPoint.
Select there, paste that.
That has now added the chart.
And again, I can then edit the chart
to change the text within the chart,
Arial, make it slightly bigger.
That will let me make any amendments.
I can also add various other
features, the axis titles.
I can format the charts so the style
and the colour, make changes to that.
And one of the things that is a
benefit is that you can actually make a
change to the data in the spreadsheet.
And then if you go back to
your presentation, it will
automatically update the data.
So it is linked the chart
to the actual presentation.